Darren Labithiotis

Remote Senior Software Engineer

labithiotis@gmail.com (+44) 7545 615129 Alexanderhofstraße 36. Millstatt. 9872

I'm a passionate software engineer, with over 8+ years of experience. My experience ranges from building one pagers, full-stacks, single page application, to mobile apps via React Native. I've used various libraries over the years and these are the ones I'm intimately familiar with: Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Redux, Sass/Less, Node, Express/Koa, MongoDb, SQL, along with a fairly deep knowledge of DevOps on the AWS and GCP platforms.

Before becoming a software engineer I studied and worked as a game designer, thus I'm very proficient at Photoshop and Sketch, these skills have combined with my coding ability to help me deliver projects to a high standard and have a keen eye for detail and UX.

At the end of 2017 I decided to live abroad in the Austrian mountains, moving away from central London where I'd lived for 10 years. Since then, I have been working as full-time remote developer. Working remotely has benefits, from being focused, less distracted, to no commute time and genuinely a better way of working. While still being able to attend meetings, stand-ups, and pair program as if I was co-located.

Skills

Agile Pair Programming, TDD, Kanban, Sprints, Retros, Measure to iterate.

Languages Typescript, JavaScript ES5/ES6, JSX, HTML, CSS, Less/Sass, Node, NoSQL, SQL, Bash, Terraform.

Libraries React, React Native, Styled-Components, Redux, Jest, Mocha, Backbone, jQuery, Express, Koa, Underscore/Lodash, Handlebars, Jade, Moment, Numeral, Bootstrap, AWS, MongoDb, MySQL, PostGres, Redis, Webpack, Parcel.

Tools Webstorm, VSCode, Sketch, Photoshop, Slack, Asana, Jira, Miro, Browserstack, Looker, MixPanel, Segment, StatHat, DataDog, Rollbar, CircleCi, TeamViewer.

Employment

Senior Software Engineer @ Triptease

April 2016 - Present

During my tenor I worked across the suite of the products Triptease offers, from their price check widget to the backend services for acquiring prices from online travel agents, to the backend platform for hoteliers to manage and review how well the Triptease products performed.

React Native Mobile App - SC Field Guide

https://apple.co/2JJTjlc

Solely built a React Native mobile app for a highly anticipated game, Star Citizen. Built in my spare time to fill the gap where there was limited apps in the market to provide info for this game.

Head of Development @ Boppl

April 2013 - April 2016

Hands on developer while managing a team of developers, from Java backenders' to iOS / Android devs while building Boppl's CMS for their mobile ordering platform. The CMS was built using Backbone, jQuery, Handlebars, Require.js plus others.

Fullstack Developer as Contractor @ Prism Digital

(contract) July 2015 - Present

Solely built a full-stack website using Node, Express, Jade, MongoDB for a recruitment website

Software Artist & Project Management @ Waterfront

February 2009 - February 2013

Created and managed the development of lots of highly branded games for a STB company.

Education

1st Class Hons (BSc) in Computer Games Design 2005 - 2008 Staffordshire University MongoDB Certified Certificate 2015 MongoDB University

Languages

English